# REBECCA SCHRADER

34E Fernleigh Drive, Castleknock, Dublin 15

Mobile: (353) 0838 72 2970 / Email: <a href="mailto:RMSchrader1994@gmail.com">RMSchrader1994@gmail.com</a> Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/Rebecca-schrader-076731109

Website: https://schrader169.wixsite.com/mysite

### **PROFILE**

Qualified Multimedia Developer with a Bachelor's degree in Communications from Salisbury University, and Level 5 Diploma in Software Development from the Code Institute, Dublin. Three years relevant work experience in Marketing, Education, Travel, Non-Profit, and Public Relations settings. Creates and produces original content from storyboard through post-production, while demonstrating a keen ability to creatively interpret a brief and contribute insightfully to business discussions. Seeking to apply and grow my skills in a junior developer/designer position within a dynamic setting where my perspective is valued and my limits are tested.

### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Diploma in Software Development (EQF Level 5) Code Institute, Dublin.

Jan - Apr 2018

Introductory Certificate in CSS & XHTML College of Southern Maryland, La Plata, Maryland U.S.A.

Aug - Oct 2017

B.A. Honours (2:1), Communication Arts (Media Production) Salisbury University, Maryland U.S.A.

Aug 2013 - Jun 2017

## RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Freelance Writer, iWriter

May 2020 - Present

Produce professionally-written daily articles to client specifications and often to tight deadlines. Specialising in technology, social media and gaming.

### Marketing & Programme Intern, WorkandTravel.ie

Oct 2019 – Apr 2020

Maintained and updated multiple social media outlooks (Facebook, Instagram, & Instagram) with original multimedia content. Manned information stands and gave live presentations that increased company's presence on college campuses nationwide. Provided administrative support through interviews, phone inquiries & application review.

### Multimedia Specialist, Aunua Academy

Sep 2019 – Present

Provided photographic, video production, and website management services to Aunua Academy, an Irish non-profit and global provider of free education for mental health provided by industry leading experts. (Part-time, unpaid).

**Accommodation Assistant, The Key Collection** 

Mar - Oct 2019

In-Store Demonstrator, Field Management Ireland

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

# Communications Intern, Irish Academy of Public Relations

Jan - Jun 2017

Filmed Academy Director Ellen Gunning's presentations at national-level conference and corporate events, and classroom activity in courses held at the Academy. Successfully produced over 150 promotional and educational videos from my footage (often under intense time pressure), and distributed them to an international online audience. Updated, maintained, and significantly expanded the Academy's social media footprint, especially on YouTube.

# **Teacher's Aide, Salisbury University**

**Sept – Dec 2016** 

Assisted in teaching 2D Animation undergraduate class, and led lessons in absence of more senior Faculty. Commended by Professor for the technical quality of material produced by my students, all of whom successfully completed the course.

### **Distance Learning Facilitator, Salisbury University**

Sept 2015 - Dec 2016

Worked unsupervised to set up, monitor, and troubleshoot digital broadcasts between Salisbury University main campus and satellite sites. Achieved 100 percent success rate in providing unbroken communications to students on remote campuses state-wide.

### **TECHNICAL & IT SKILLS**

- Software Development: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ruby/Python, GitHub, MySQL, Django
- Administrative & Creative: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook); Social Media, including YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn
- **Audio-Visual:** Avid, Sony Vegas, Adobe Creative Cloud (After Effects, Dreamweaver, Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop, Premiere)
- Website (with Portfolio): <a href="https://schrader169.wixsite.com/mysite">https://schrader169.wixsite.com/mysite</a>

#### LEADERSHIP POSITIONS

- 1. Rose from Audio Technician to Executive Producer at SU-TV public access television channel. (Sep 2013 Dec 2016)
- 2. Co-Leader of Brownie Troop #110, as part of a non-profit mentoring programme for underprivileged children in Wicomico County, Maryland. (Sep 2015 May 2016)

## **INTERESTS**

- 1. International travel. I've travelled independently to Canada, Germany, France, Switzerland and Scotland, and in company to Australia, New Zealand, England and Wales. I enjoy the feeling of confidence and independence I get when I travel on my own and navigate successfully through situations I've never been in before. It makes me realize I can take on things beyond my usual comfort zone, and make a success of them.
- 2. I perform freelance Web design and development for small business customers (e.g. https://aureliadelyallregencystyle.co.uk/). This allows me to practice my creative design and development skills, and to keep my software skills current during those periods when I am employed outside my field.

U.S. / U.K. dual national References available on request